<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Akadup Tinker Site</title>
    <link>https://waynedupreez1.github.io/AkadupTinker/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Akadup Tinker Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 13:42:49 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://waynedupreez1.github.io/AkadupTinker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Freecad NAS enclosure</title>
      <link>https://waynedupreez1.github.io/AkadupTinker/posts/2020_10_11_cad_for_nas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 08:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waynedupreez1.github.io/AkadupTinker/posts/2020_10_11_cad_for_nas/</guid>
      <description>Description I love to tinker with things, generally my computers and sometimes when you tinker you tend to screw up and loose data, sometimes very important data like your wedding photos and everything else.
Yes you read correctly I lost my wedding photos, all of it. This happened whilst moving from linux to windows and not backing up properly, yeah I know pretty stupid.
Fortunately with some more tinkering and running some recovery software for a few days I managed to recover all my photos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STM32F0xx DigitalIO AnalogIn Rust</title>
      <link>https://waynedupreez1.github.io/AkadupTinker/posts/2020_09_13_stm32f0_adio_rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 08:42:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waynedupreez1.github.io/AkadupTinker/posts/2020_09_13_stm32f0_adio_rust/</guid>
      <description>Description As mentioned in STM32F0xx DigitalIO AnalogIn PCB one of the main reasons for me to take on this project is to learn some more rust lang. If rust is useful in an embedded setting I definitely will not subject myself to C again anytime soon, just kidding I like you C&amp;hellip;.nah not really.
Setup Hardware  Target =&amp;gt; STM32F030  This seemed like a pretty reasonable Cortex M0 chip the variation I use sports around 35 useful pins, 64K ROM and 8K RAM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STM32F0xx DigitalIO AnalogIn PCB</title>
      <link>https://waynedupreez1.github.io/AkadupTinker/posts/2020_03_30_stm32f0_adio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 09:45:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waynedupreez1.github.io/AkadupTinker/posts/2020_03_30_stm32f0_adio/</guid>
      <description>Description After killing my backplane idea I decided to try my hand at a distributed IO type system.
STM32F0 ADIO PCB I decided to use a stm32F030 mcu on this for 2 reasons: 1. its cheap about 1USD 2. rust is fully supported.
There is also a few selectable options set with solder bridges, I will talk about these options all through the post.
Digital: I allowed for 8 selectable inputs or outputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Killing the Industrial BackPlane</title>
      <link>https://waynedupreez1.github.io/AkadupTinker/posts/2020_08_30_killing_the_industrial_backplane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 09:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waynedupreez1.github.io/AkadupTinker/posts/2020_08_30_killing_the_industrial_backplane/</guid>
      <description>Description Killing of the Industrial backplane and the reasons why.
Reasons The main reason for killing this project is because of economics, let me explain.
The idea with this system was to create a generic backplane, then create a cpu module for every controller board that we want to interface with the backplane. These cpu modules could technically be anything stm32 blue pill&amp;rsquo;s or raspberry pi&amp;rsquo;s or any cheap controller. The typical size of the cpu module would be about 50mm x 50mm which would cost 15USD for a 4 layer board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eeprom 34c04</title>
      <link>https://waynedupreez1.github.io/AkadupTinker/posts/2020_03_08_eeprom_34c04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 11:38:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waynedupreez1.github.io/AkadupTinker/posts/2020_03_08_eeprom_34c04/</guid>
      <description>Description So after geting some PCB&amp;rsquo;s made I decided to try my hand at writing drivers for the 34C04 EEPROM I2C chips that I use to identify each PCB plugged into the backplane board.
I decided to write this in rust as my C language foo is not so great, also rust is cool and I want to try it out for embedded work as I already use it for pc code development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industrial BackPlane</title>
      <link>https://waynedupreez1.github.io/AkadupTinker/posts/2020_03_08_industrial_backplane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 11:38:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waynedupreez1.github.io/AkadupTinker/posts/2020_03_08_industrial_backplane/</guid>
      <description>Description I have managed to get some PCB&amp;rsquo;s designed based on my requirements. Here is some 3D models of the first few boards I am getting made.
Backplane PCB This board is essentially the main component all other boards will plug into.
Some features I tried to nail on this one:  Allowed for up to 4 boards to be plugged in. Each slot is addressable. Provide connectors for 24V, 3V3 and 5V to be connected directly into the backplane (This could be replaced by a plug in board).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://waynedupreez1.github.io/AkadupTinker/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 13:42:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://waynedupreez1.github.io/AkadupTinker/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi and welcome to my site my name is Wayne du Preez.
My background is in electronics with experience in:
 PCB Development for products ranging from 300kW PSU&amp;rsquo;s to range finder laser testers. Custom test system development for military products. Off the Shelf test system usage for bed of nails production systems. Embedded software development in C. Linux administration on production machines. Ansible configurtion and usage for LXD, KVM, Windows and Linux machine configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>